Finding Aid for the Laura Riding Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Laura Riding Collection
1923-1933
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0365
.42 linear_feet
Scope and Content Note
The Laura Riding Collection, 1923-1933, includes correspondence, poetry, and lists ofpotential subscribers to The Fugitive magazine. The collection is very minimal, containing 7 letters, 6 poems, and several pages oflists and notecards. The focus of this collection is Laura Riding’s connection to The Fugitive Magazine.
- Correspondence, Outgoing
  - Laura Riding Gottschalk to Allen Tate, 24 Oct 1923 (Folder 1, Box 1)
  - Laura Riding Gottschalk to Allen Tate (poem "In the Beginning included), 12 Dec 1923 (Folder 1, Box 1)
  - Laura Gottschalk to Fugitive Editor, 20 Jul1924 (Folder 1, Box 1)
  - Laura Riding to The Editors, The Kansas City Star, 5 Mar 1939 (Folder 2, Box 1)
  - Laura Jackson to Mr. Hamilton, 25 Mar 1971 (Folder 2, Box 1)
  - Laura (Riding) Jackson to The Editors [NYR ?], 22 Dec 1983 (Folder 2, Box 1)
  - Laura Riding to Allen Tate, File 3 Undated (Folder 3, Box 1)
  - Laura Riding to Unidentified, Undated (Folder 3, Box 1)
  - Laura Riding to Unidentified, Undated (Folder 3, Box 1)
  - Laura Riding to Unidentified, Undated (Folder 3, Box 1)
  - Laura Riding to Unidentified, Undated (Folder 3, Box 1)
- Manuscripts, Poetry
  - “Apocryphal Number 1”, File 4 9 Jun 1933 (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - “Apocryphal Number 2”, 16 Jun 1933 (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - “Apocryphal Number 3”, 27 Jun 1933 (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - Prospectus for Focus, A Monthly Register, Undated (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - “A Need for Hell”, Undated (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - “On Sophistication”, Undated (Folder 4, Box 1)
- Miscellaneous Materials
  - “Some Notes on Poetry and Poets in this Century, and My Influence" PN Review Vol. 6, No. 1 (Folder 5, Box 1)
  - Questionnaire for The Directory of British and American Writers, (1970) (Folder 6, Box 1)
  - The Fugitive (Magazine) 1922-1925 Riding Subscription Lists (Folder 7, Box 1)
  - 6 notecards with names and personal information (Folder 7, Box 1)
  - Page with nanles and addresses (Folder 7, Box 1)
  - Titled "People I have recently circularized myself’ (Folder 7, Box 1)
- Subject Files, Laura Riding
  - Obituaries- (Folder 8, Box 1)
    - Program printed for persons attending the memorial service for Laura (Riding) Jackson
    - The Independent, September 5, 1991
    - PN Review (Poetry Nation Review) NovlDec 1991 Vol. 18, No.2
  - “Something Different: Laura Riding Jackson’s Response" by Amber Vogel, Carolina Quarterly, 1995 (Folder 9, Box 1)
  - “The Houseguest from Hell" by Jonathon Mahler, Talk September, 1999 (Folder 10, Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Items (Folder 11, Box 1)
    - Note from Random House that accompanied review copies of Collected Poems of Laura Riding
    - Martin Seymour-Smith’s response to Laura (Riding) Jackson’s July 16, 1982 Letter to the Editor of the Times Literary Supplement
    - Photocopy of Invitation to Poetry n’ Polo, a benefit for the Laura (Riding) Jackson Home Preservation Foundation, Inc., Vero Beach, Florida
    - The Home-Place, Spring 1996-A Publication of the Laura (Riding) Jackson Home Preservation Foundation, Inc.